doctorslounge.com 2018-12-22

# Privacy statement - Doctors Lounge(TM)

web.archive.org / [web](https://web/) / 20181222215437id_ / https%3A /  / www.doctorslounge.com / privacy.htm

* * *

### June 21, 2007

Welcome. Doctors Lounge would like to thank you for visiting our website. We are pleased to have the opportunity to help make the Internet a secure, private, and reliable place to share information and conduct business. This privacy policy explains how we collect and use information from our website visitors. All of Doctors Lounge divisions prescribe to essentially the same information collection and use practices, and all of these practices are stated in this privacy policy. If a practice is specific to a particular division in Doctors Lounge, this policy will describe that practice in detail and refer directly to the appropriate division.

> ### Doctors Lounge Privacy Policy statement, addresses the following issues:

  * The websites and information covered by this Privacy Policy; 
  * Exactly what information may be collected and how it will be used; 
  * The consequences, if any, resulting from your refusal to provide personal information;
  * Whether a company uses cookies, tracks IP addresses, or uses other passive means to collect information; 
  * Who, if anyone, is collecting your personal information; 
  * With whom, if anyone, is your personal information shared; 
  * What is a company's policy regarding links to third party sites; 
  * What choices you have with regard to the use of your personal information; 
  * How you can access, and if necessary, change the personal information a company collects and maintains;
  * How a company ensures data security, quality, and integrity; and,
  * Where and how to ask questions or file complaints. 

* * *

### What does this Privacy Policy apply to?

This privacy policy applies to the website operated by Doctors Lounge:

Please note that this privacy policy applies only to information submitted and collected online through the website(s) listed above, and does not apply to information that may be collected by Doctors Lounge offline. In addition, this privacy policy applies only to sites maintained by Doctors Lounge and not to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we link. Doctors Lounge is therefore not responsible for the content or activities provided on such sites.

* * *

### What types of information does Doctors Lounge collect and how will it be used? 

Doctors Lounge only collects information on a voluntary basis. The personal information Doctors Lounge collects is used almost exclusively for communications purposes and will usually take the form of: (1) Doctors Lounge Membership registration form; (2) a consumer complaint or inquiry directed to the Support Team; (3) Doctors Lounge survey; (4) Doctors Lounge Medical Forums and other medical services; (5) Doctors Lounge referral services; (6) Doctors Lounge's newsletter; and/or, (7) other general information contained in an email (e.g., comments). The types of information that may be requested for each activity and the way the information may be used are detailed below.

**Doctors Lounge Membership registration form**  
Visitors that wish to participate in the activities on the site are required to complete Doctors Lounge Membership registration form. The requested information may include the individual's name, address, telephone, electronic mail (email) address, job, area of specialty, qualifications as well as demographic data. Doctors Lounge uses this information to contact the individual regarding participation and, if eligible, to communicate with such a member on an ongoing basis regarding certification and compliance.

**Consumer Complaints Directed to the Support Team**  
From time to time, the Support Team receives complaints or inquiries regarding the Doctors Lounge services. When a complaint or inquiry is received, the Support Team promptly investigates the complaint or inquiry, and then, when appropriate, responds to the individual who sent the complaint or inquiry via the e-mail address from where the request originated.

**Doctors Lounge Survey**  
Any one of the Doctors Lounge divisions may conduct surveys. The surveys are conducted strictly for internal profiling purposes and only keep track of anonymous demographic data.

**Doctors Lounge Medical Services**  
Doctors Lounge Medical Services are designed to help both physicians and consumers in extending their knowledge of various medical topics and keep up to date with current medical information. These services include; Doctors Lounge Medical Forums. Some of our services are conducted through a partnership.

**Doctors Lounge Newsletter**  
Visitors who wish to subscribe to the Doctors Lounge newsletter will be asked to provide their e-mail address as well as demographic data. The submitted e-mail address is then used to send you, via e-mail, our quarterly newsletter and to otherwise keep you informed as to what's going on at the Doctors Lounge.

**General Information Contained in Email**  
Doctors Lounge's website provides a number of links through which an online visitor can e-mail us. Doctors Lounge collects personal information contained in the e-mail for the purpose of responding to a consumer's questions and/or comments.

No matter what method we use to collect information and no matter how we use that information, we will only collect the information deemed reasonably necessary to fulfill your online requests and our legitimate business objectives.

* * *

### What happens if I refuse to provide my personal information to Doctors Lounge?

If you choose not to submit personal information when requested, you may not be able to access certain areas of our site and may considerably limit the services we can provide you. To simply use our site, however, you do not need to give us any personal information.

* * *

### Does Doctors Lounge use cookies, track IP addresses or use other passive means to collect information?

**Cookies**  
Doctors Lounge uses cookies on its Medical Forums to allow registered users to use the forums. A "cookie" is a small file or record-keeping device that websites often store on a user's computer.

**IP Addresses**  
Doctors Lounge may collect your IP address for safety and security purposes. An IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer every time you log on to the Internet. 

* * *

### Who is collecting my personal information?

The information that you disclose while visiting our website is collected by Doctors Lounge or a vendor on Doctors Lounge's behalf, and is used in the manner specified above.

* * *

### With whom does Doctors Lounge share my personal information?

From time to time, Doctors Lounge may employ and share your personal information with vendors who use it solely to provide support for the internal operations of Doctors Lounge's website(s) (e.g., technical support, order fulfillment, and newsletter delivery). These entities will not use your personal information for any other purpose, and have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of the personal information they obtain from us.

It is our policy not to sell or rent your personal information. We may, however, disclose your personal information to outside third parties as described in this privacy policy. In addition, we may also disclose your personal information in the good faith belief that we are required to do so by law, or that doing so is reasonably necessary to comply with legal processes; respond to any claims; or, to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Doctors Lounge or the public.

Customers may receive information about third party services that are likely to be of interest. Users of our free service will initially be opted in to this program while customers signing up any of our paid service can choose to opt in. Customers can opt out by clicking on the link provided in the email or by visiting our site and opting out at any time.

We may also use personally identifiable End-User information to provide targeted content and commerce opportunities to End-Users based on their demographic and behavioral information. This does not apply to the personal medical information collected in the "Ask a Doctor"/ "Medical Forums" section. We do not share the personal medical information of our users.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways or for reasons unrelated to the ones described above without also providing an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

* * *

### What is the policy of Doctors Lounge regarding links to third party sites?

You should be aware that while you are on a website operated by Doctors Lounge, you may be directed to other sites that are beyond our control and for which we are not responsible. Because we cannot guarantee that the privacy policies of these websites meet our high standards, we recommend that you read the privacy policy of the website to which you link before you submit any personal information.

* * *

### Can I choose how my personal information is used?

If you wish to opt-out from receiving our newsletter or any other communication, please contact us, at any time, [via e-mail](mailto:webmaster@doctorslounge.com?subject=Privacy%20Info). We will be happy to honor your request.  

* * *

### How can I access my personal information?

If you wish to review, update, or delete any personal information that we may have collected about you, please contact us [via e-mail](mailto:webmaster@doctorslounge.com?subject=Privacy%20Info).

* * *

### What safeguards does Doctors Lounge use to protect my personal information?

Doctors Lounge maintains appropriate safeguards that ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the personal information we collect from all users. Personal information collected by Doctors Lounge is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public and is only accessible by authorized employees. We also have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.

* * *

### How do I ask a question or file a complaint?

If you have any questions, complaints or comments regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us [via e-mail](mailto:webmaster@doctorslounge.com?subject=Privacy%20Info).

By using this site, you signify your assent to the Doctors Lounge Online Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use this site. We reserve the right to make changes to this Policy. Please check back from time to time to ensure you are aware of these changes. Your continued use of this site will signify your acceptance of these changes.

## Are you a Doctor, Pharmacist, PA or a Nurse?

**Join the Doctors Lounge online medical community**

  * **Editorial activities:** Publish, peer review, edit online articles.

  * **Ask a Doctor Teams:** Respond to patient questions and discuss challenging presentations with other members.
